I don't know all the records get to me in the amount of City Council for Tuesday, March 4, 2020, bye.
But again, let's get to the personal taxes. We have none. Three kinds lists.
Much to approve.
Thank you.
Hi.
Four kinds lists for Vance Board.
Much to approve.
Hi.
Sorry.
Good afternoon.
Good morning.
Good to see you.
Have a great day.
Hi.
Good afternoon.
Andattle.
The Far Fog to samo.
He stepped for number five for weakin.
Perfect.
So line out from five presentation of check from Nestle Pirinif Turn mostra,
I bring in the animal shelter.
So we would like to bring out Maysi.
And then I wrote both from Pirinif.
We got Gene Michaels and pronounce your name.
Mostly—
Okay, yeah
We are honored to accept this generous donation from Curina.
This support will enable us to complete the first phase
and construct the our new dog park, including the installation
of a simple fifth-thincing to create safe areas
for both large and small dogs.
The park will eventually feature other amenities such as water
fountain, seating areas for owners, and grasscut
and entrances for riding welcoming spaces
for the community to engage and pay nine socialization.
We are excited to collaborate with Curina to the answer.
Real quick, I want to thank you, Jen, and everybody, Prina.
Whenever Prina first came to my ally, we met with him
at the Chamber office, and this was a project we discussed.
And so, thank you guys for coming through and making it happen.
We have a lot of people in town that ask us as a council
for this great thing in dog park.
So it's going to be exciting to be able to let the community know
that Curina's making it happen.
So, thank you guys for coming down.
I'm appreciate it.
And I'm proud to be a part of this organization.
All right, six, presentation from the bottom area
economic development services.
Let's change the view hall.
All right.
Thank you.
Good evening.
Mayor, council is always a pleasure to be before the council
to update you on some of the things that we are working on.
Tonight, specifically, I wanted to update you on the housing study
for the Miami-American Economic Development Services conducting.
We did not enter into that project.
Along, we have some very amazing partners, including the city of Miami,
several businesses and individuals.
And of course, it's hard to do anything without the support of our amazing
tribal partners.
All of those entities have come to be possible.
This study goes actually back to our economic development, action plan,
that we developed last spring.
One of the initiatives in there was to address that.
From that, we form a housing committee to start the process of figuring out how we're going to go about viewing the study.
We have to determine the support from that housing committee.
And as a result of that, we eventually hire a firm out of Dallas, that's what's called catlist incorporated.
They are in the process now wrapping up our housing study. You should have it complete within the next couple weeks.
At the same time, catlist was viewing our study. We also negotiated on behalf of the city of Bro, to hard catalysts to do wear study.
While we are at the end of our process, Bro, this kind of just from the middle of their process.
The goal is for both of those studies to be completed. That saves us a little bit of a modest trip.
That has to be made to get the different locations.
And just for the record, Bro, pay for their own.
No city funds.
My humble funds.
So what I'm going to talk to you today is something I'm just going to get some of the highlights.
I'm not going to get into the whole study, again, we're still tweaking of these things.
But I thought I'd give you the basic information from the study.
How it pertains to my end of answering the questions that you may have.
So first thing I want to do is since January 1, we have had some changes to our award directors.
We have some new members. We have some long standing board members that have rotated all of creating some opportunities for it.
Some new fresh blood.
So it's made on our board.
One of those fresh ones is in the audience's eyes.
Mr. Michaels, we have to have her.
But just to let you know, our executive committee is headed up by Cameron Wilkins.
He is our chairperson. He is from Security Bank.
Dr. Kyle Stafford is our vice chairperson.
And Blake Landy from Security.
Our first national bank is our secretary of the Treasury.
Our board members can be asked to.
Our board members can go to Big Bowers from Goldbiber.
Our all-searched mayor of Maryland.
German Wibles.
Black Eagle Grant.
James Barnes, Tyler Klein, city manager.
We should turn the old board board.
Jared Cash, manager of Walmart, 2% under and down.
Brett Hayes, a USRT loan.
My name is Mayor plus Parker.
Sean Taylor, with our best name.
A new member as well as a nomination chairperson.
We have a supernol.
She holds the seat.
That is the end.
travel counsel. So they're travel counsel, get one seat on our board. They determine if you
they want to represent them in this year. It's chairperson, super on.
Fisher going to Mission of I. Fartist. I mean, of course, there's a fan here in the
town at France on our board. Of course, there's a lot of stuff in here.
To keep you asked this, because with me tonight is our newest employee, she went full of time
with a January one. She was working part-time for the Chamber of Commerce and for May's
last year, about half of the year, now she's full of time. We got her to switch over to the
dark side. Enjoy this and have a good development. And we're very happy to have her.
So let's talk a little bit about the study.
For this study, aims to provide a comprehensive analysis of our local housing market,
looking at a lot of different factors. Well, what we're trying to determine is what business
that status of our housing market today. What do we anticipate it being five years from now,
two years from now, 20 years from now? And so, Atlas has been working very hard looking at all the
different conditions that can affect housing here in Miami. To find out where the gaps are, where
our opportunities to create new housing. And you have to factor in employment, growth, community,
expansion, demographic shifts, all of those things have a big impact on our housing needs.
I'll leave today about what they're going to project at the end of the next. And so you take all of that
in the context and they, you know, they've been doing this for a long time. It wasn't at all through
the algorithm. And that helps to determine what our needs are. And we'll talk about those here in just a second.
The process was a pretty detailed and deforested process. They come in doing a
initial assessment of the current market. They go through all of our neighborhoods, their gathering
information from realtors. They went to city of Miami. I know they went and pulled housing permits.
These are bad nature to see how many housing companies have been doing for the last several years.
They did that with the other communities in the area as well. Just trying to get a build for the market.
They're looking at affordability and demand. What do we have? What is available? What is it costs?
And then the last phase of the study, which I can bring in to tonight, but if they conclude this study,
was some recommendations on how to go about addressing the housing needs that came up.
That was a big impact on the study. And I don't think it's any stranger to anybody in this room.
It was our good friend flight. Flooding is a major problem. It was an interesting to read their comments.
the share-comments in regard to flood.
So this is a third party on the outside,
looking in assessing where we are as a community,
continuing to account all of the factors
that can have an impact on not only current housing
but future housing.
And they still are quite a bit of a time talking
about flooding, and they're studied.
Now, I don't normally do this,
but I'm going to read work for work, what they wrote,
just to solve for what they wrote out for the New York 40.
The impacts of flooding on Miami
extend four beyond the physical property damage,
creating cascading effects that touch every aspect
of the community and economy.
From your road to property values,
and municipal revenues, to weaken social cohesion
and reduced economic mobility.
The consequences of flood-induced vacancies
are profound and poor region.
Dressing these challenges requires a comprehensive understanding
of the interconnected nature of housing, economics,
the community health, as well as a long-term commitment
to building resilience against future flooding.
Those are words of the majority of the behind us.
And I think they speak volumes about the impact of flood-induced.
One thing, I spoke at really, really,
today, I talked a little bit about this.
You know what's the term?
Every time I am a city of Miami,
I don't understand all of the residents who have filed
the creation of the nation.
Anytime we see movement in the wall of cities,
anytime we get close to or get a win on the federal level
in regards to the real licensing efforts
by G or D A with the federal energy regulatory commission,
we see a lot of the same tricks that come in the past.
Repeated.
I mean, what I'm going to tell you before I go
and you further into this, is I'm going to give you
some paper advice, I gave rotary today,
and that's this beware of the false problems.
Every time this happens, and we're already hearing it,
G or D A, we use every tool at the end.
They will use politicians.
They will use your neighbors.
They will use your friends, your family, whoever they can get,
the lens on the sympathetic ear.
We try to tell you that, you know, I can't
we all just sit down at the table.
Have you heard that before?
See, my lady, you got a blessing, you heard that?
I get that all the time.
And every time we get close to a major break that I hear,
all we have to do, here's what I'm going to tell you.
In the entire history, the operation of the fiscal demand.
Think about everything.
on the GREA's, every day in the city of Miami,
and in that entire time, at the ever-lived one.
So why would we now, all of a sudden, stop and say,
OK, sure, let's sit down at the table.
You're fighting these pipes for a reason.
You're fighting the whole amount of work
with the damage they've already done.
And fighting, it's a mitigate, any future damage.
By building in some conditions to their new license,
they're going to get the license.
That's nothing that we'll go.
The question is, what can we add to that license
that help try to hold them, of power,
that's the fact that that's the investigation.
Preation of the data.
That being said, let's talk about our needs.
So this section focuses on what are the liter,
what's the liter occupied demand for Miami and auto-organized.
And so you can see from all to family housing,
we need a total of 269 units.
Now, they actually break it down by rent.
So you've got, I mean, a hundred nine units of room units
that take that are in a cost of $100,000.
And it goes up.
This is actually common in the end at nature,
to all due places, but that's the total rent or demand we have.
Today, let us take into account what we may need
down the road, right?
So as we continue to work, try to bring in new business
and industry to our community, and we create more jobs,
and we create more demand on housing,
at least numbers actually go up.
But right now, in Miami and auto-organized,
we need to do it in six, nine real units today.
Now, first, for all our occupied, single family homes,
at numbers 274, and you break it down, homes under 200,000, 65.
This is what I thought it was going to be interesting.
All of them, 250 to 350,000, we need 76 of those.
But then when you think about that, I think back to,
you know, we sold a property in our industrial park
to the lives of the pipe company, and they brought a plant manager
over here from California.
He lives on brand land.
I don't want to take on Jim, Jim, where do you want to go?
But as we continue, you got a BBCB who wants to expand and add a completely different
different product.
And what they're all doing on higher people, they're going to pay you the latest, they're
going to bring in another manager, probably, from there.
We don't want these folks, they're good people, they are business leaders in our community.
They've been involved in our work because if they live here, they're going to shop here, they're
going to generate sales taxes, they're going to be a utility customer, a much greater
income.
We just don't have any, so again, those are just some of the highlights from the study, there's
a lot more from it.
It's 95 pages here, we're citing 95 pages to that order to take it up, but it's important
information.
And why is it important?
The only way we can solve this is if we have this data and we can put it in the hands.
We have a meeting, it's very risky to go, very risky to go, with a developer who's looking at putting
a project out there, we sat down with him, there was a few of them who's there, and we talked
about the housing study, he asked, what do you have in the copy of the preliminary report, so
I should read these numbers, and it was like I had just, you know, given the person's size, but
up because it was exactly what I'm looking for.
Now I know what I can build, I know what I can sell, and suddenly the conversation shifted from
what can you help me with on an infrastructure or to help me with this or that, it was like, okay,
I think we're good, this is what I mean, it's nice guys, appreciate it, great meeting, that was wonderful, and this
is the hands of every, so just enclosing, you know, if we could just meet even a portion of the demand that we have for
a housing, we could say, if we're going to go out and try to recruit more industry and work doesn't
start.
They're going to bring people with good places, instead of this, we have people in our community
right now who are living in housing that I would consider.
is below their beans or below their level of income.
Why?
Because there's actually no place for them to get them.
We need new houses.
We need up they to the bottom of houses,
so that we can change the trajectory else
to get out of the hover community, right?
And again, I got up the way with the point.
But we need all we need around you as we need to know,
devices, whatever we should do,
pay attention to the names and medical professionals
or our aging families who are in larger homes
who may be looking to step down
and free up some of those older nicer and larger homes.
And again, there's opportunities on this part.
Yes, there are challenges.
We know one big challenge is just what?
But you know what?
We can't learn high from it.
We have to embrace it.
We have to hit it on.
We have to maintain the fight.
That means that it doesn't have to.
You know what, Shannon?
You've done a fantastic job with it.
It's always good to have you here.
What is it?
It's an honor to be here.
If you need to get a hold of them
with your part contact, it's a question.
What's an honor to be here?
It says, obviously, it seems as if they ever need me to read
and all they have to do is call an ask,
the partnership that we have and the relationship that we have.
We want to continue that.
And we thank you for your support and not this point.
I'll let you do that.
I have any questions.
That was great, Sharon.
I've been really excited to hear from you about this.
I knew it was coming out of the fight for a while.
Well, then again, this is just a snippet.
The information has been written in the report.
And just so you know, there was a lot more information on what I shared.
We give it all to those for the most point points that would be great.
What does it look like now?
How do you get these to developers to outsource them?
Does it make to do that?
Does it invite me to work in the event?
We're getting a bit of a new opportunity.
We're going to do a public.
I'll wait here to see you all.
I don't know if you're going to come.
We'll probably do a town hall type of you.
We're going to ask anybody who knows the developers
that's contacts with the developers to let them know about the town hall meeting.
We will have, we will have science, she and anyone that signs in who wants to copy,
we will email them about copying, which is going to get down at us for themselves.
I said, this is something that's happening for lunch.
It doesn't, it was any good to spend, by the way, $50,000 on a study for the children to collect those.
If we don't go and turn over every stone to get this in the hands of every single developer,
we'll be coming contact with, then we wasted $50,000, so we arrived at this.
Yes, we're at our public town hall meeting, we're going to do our best for a blast of our TV, our social media.
And great shirt, by the way, at least when they can't listen to that.
So, the budget method is 25, that's 17.
Library of Receiving, it's been equal to 5K.
For the American Library Association of Digital Literacy,
Work Shop, and Senate Grant.
So, prior to the budget resolution, that's a pretty nice tune.
In each change, the bottom line of revenues or expenditures has to go for the Council
to produce a decent, really basic.
And this, we're asking you to increase this in our budget.
Come here, and let's make a motion of minutes.
Second, please, Cruz.
Aye.
Sorry.
Aye, Sen.
Aye.
Thank you.
Eight award requisitions for qualifications are FQ25-1011,
and important giving, consultant to Harvard, and NATO.
We some proposals should serve to employ even the battler
to enjoy technical sub-service investigations of assessments.
What it does say is we need specialised people who are, it's not, but a request will follow us if it's request will follow us.
And we received through proposals on Garbo, the LTN40 selection committee.
Then we've known communications that Garbo came out.
presentations, resumes, dreams they have, so it was best. Delta came in at 27 and Marla had
scored one basically. They got one to complications. That part of the basically, the
pricing that we used, our steered, this kind of thing, what we should see at
just what's going on every night. Inside's done and it can't, Travis, the inside's actually
done. How are we looking on the budget for the project? We've got to know that.
So does this the thing we're talking about right now. That's included in that budget your years. No
Okay
I remember that. Thank you
I make a motion wait proof
God is a man who made a street board. So I have Trinity Crow here and then Missy is going to
Hollywood this too. So this is something that was brought up way before my time. Three years as a
guy who I think they came up the idea of having a main street director and a main street board. It appears
you know that we didn't we don't have bylaws or anything for this board. And so Missy now we're talking and it's like
I didn't think it was fair for us to figure out how to do the bylaws without bringing it to
Obviously the City Council to make sure they're on our agreement how it should be set up. I'm going to have a couple of meetings with
Carry bear from Main Street and it appears most Main streets in Oklahoma or like you know
The city would just give them a donation and that would be there. They're only thing that to do with them
Which obviously that's different than ours. And we have city employees that do the Main Street and we have city employees that help do the events
You know it parks that's a streets you know does barricades and stuff. So we just kind of want to talk through a couple of things
Before we sit down and do the bylaws to reflect like what the Main Street board
Operation would be so kind of that the two main things I have down and Missy talked about is
The Main Street board we assume you know it would we would report to the City Council because there were two options are the City Council or the MDRA
And then
With the City Council nominate the members to the board
You know so I'm only to all the other boards we have so it's an excellent advisory board to the City Council
They could still update the MDRA everything that's going on, but I mean it would be you know
They would report to the City Council
And then you know the bus would nominate the board
So we just wanted to get the you know kind of get that going so we could get everybody on the same page
I think it was fair for us to come in and say this is what we did without talking to the board
So I don't know what all is promised to the board three years ago because that time it wasn't a worry of mine
So
And Trinity can attest you know right now. They're pushing to get more support for Main Street because
People that are solely Main Street with those cities support. I mean they're outhouse them for money all the time
I mean that's their main thing
So
I'll turn this promise if we get the bylaws fixed in past then she'll make everything else
I just think it would be best for us if we keep it like we do every other work.
We come to here, we approve of the R, we have the liaison on our board on there so we know what's going on.
So we're going right in the end.
Agreed.
And advisory and non-body board.
Yes.
I mean non-body board.
We've been to the board on nominated new, but appointed by Liza Ritten.
I have serious concerns about the current market of the board.
And that's sort of appeared.
And what we have working versions that we are still working on, but without answers to these questions, but it could be finished.
So do you want to finish it?
And then appoint a new board as I would you ask him?
Well, the board currently is based off of the demographics created by the mainstream program from the state.
So unfortunately they fall into the guidelines.
So that's good.
But it's been falling in the guidelines so far.
I would have a moment for it.
So I don't necessarily know if I should go on this.
No, you should.
And then we will bring the bylaws back to you guys to make sure you, everybody's given it to you.
So today we're looking to, for us to approve how the board is created.
Well, who did the board reports to?
We wanted to clarify Councilor MDRA.
And as far as the board members, I mean, I guess Councilor pointed.
And we would just bring back his already on the board, you know.
But I mean, between now there was a board in.
So we're meeting for them.
Which means.
Especially if they're not going to be able to take independent action.
I mean, they won't be able to.
But I mean, I meant this morning.
So I don't know where your name is.
Well, this will help her be able to write the bylaws.
I don't even need to bring it back around.
You guys be what's mother.
Yeah.
But the first, we say.
I'm going to.
We've got a month.
Yeah.
It's the bylaws going to be a whole lot different than the CVB.
I mean, it's going to be similar.
Is it off?
Quite a bit because most of the bylaws are written for, you know, like, an outside entity.
Like, we just give you, you know, money to outside entities.
That's kind of the way the bylaws are written.
So we actually talked to Ken Waves with all us to him.
He's going to help us.
Yeah.
It works here.
Currently, the bylaws of Tory drafted the first, like, rough draft.
And I went for an entity though.
Thanks.
on other main streets, and that's why I got really confused,
so somebody had to sit me down and explain to me
that we're not doing that like other main streets.
And so now they need to be revamped, again,
to make them meet our needs.
When you swear on everybody on the same page,
is this project we started three years ago?
So we need two action motions,
or can we do a sweeping?
I mean, I don't know that you have to.
I told Tyler what's put it as possible action
just in case something comes up.
I don't know that you actually need to vote on this.
I just, my concern was if we're going to bring
somebody else in to help us finish these uh,
we don't want to spend money for nothing
and then have to start over because we get to the board
and the council with it and the council says,
well, this is not what we want it.
So we just really wanted some discussion and direction on
to solidify what the council wants in these bylaws
in those two yards.
So maybe we should vote just-
I don't think we can.
Yeah, one would get the Bible then we can vote on it.
I just wanted to see-
Yeah, I wanted to be sure.
We're all doing what we should do.
But I wanted the possible action just in case something came up.
I just wanted to make sure everybody's on the same page.
Go with it.
Yeah.
Try to do you have anything you need at it?
I don't know.
We've got Mr. Now, so we can work on our own
and our own five of the ones you think-
Yeah, we talked about me during the five of the ones he threw
for his former injury.
Yeah.
Which was-
So that was the reason why I was set up with injury
in the first place as my understanding.
Yeah, but we can, you know, just pull it out
because it's been a mess.
We got that grant for the way of finding sign.
Right.
And it has been-
I mean, finance is going to test this.
It has been like a mess.
Trying to get that.
Oh, so I have him separate.
It's really better anyway.
I see what he knows.
He takes it to do that.
The five of the ones he threw takes a while.
So what would it mean to me, Tom, for grants for my street?
This is going to go right in.
We could possibly leave the loose.
We have to hang on to that.
We can't lose that way.
Find it.
We find it.
You're going to go so far for, especially, projects like she'll have got her.
What kind of thing is until you get the new set up?
I think we'll stay the way it is.
And you should be able to interim operate under MBR.
And you should be able to still as his interim operate under MBR.
That shouldn't be problem.
But I mean, turn it.
It's been a mess.
I'm trying to get that way of finding a sign, I mean, because it's like A, it was down
in the room.
Yeah.
And then it expires.
That we can't lose that.
That's so.
That'll be wonderful.
We can get that way of finding a sign.
Especially done and in the ground before your event, that'd be amazing.
People come into town and fall in pretty signs.
Yeah.
I'm every angle.
What else do you need to be?
I don't know.
I don't.
Jen.
How's the new business?
The first office is is there be any issues if we cancel the next meeting and did everything on the following meeting.
We have a lot of staff is going to be gone.
I'll person be gone too.
On vacation.
You know, it's spring breaks.
I don't know.
We have a lot of people gone on spring breaks.
So if we moved everything to the 25th on that week, March 25th, it would be a scheduled work session.
But we would just have everything then.
Yep.
Tell me.
Okay.
Awesome.
And then the second thing is to make the board aware.
The school has asked us they are going to write a grant.
Or they want to write a grant for Joe Pollock Field for new lives and polls and stuff.
Maybe some other upgrades.
But because the city owns the field, we would have been a fishery of the grant.
We would be the one that would submit the grant.
They would do all the work for it, but we would submit it as a city of my own.
And we just want to make the board aware of it.
And obviously we would track any financing and we would run the financing to the city.
And the financial will not finance but the finances to it.
So.
Department of Kevin.
Did you hear it on that discussion before?
Yeah.
So they were talking about they gave that a building on the field.
Right.
That is a little bit.
You actually met with the school.
Yep.
There is a reason.
I think.
I think that other discussion was with a different superintendent.
Different director.
So it's still the plan.
So I think the board was a lot closer.
Yeah.
I think it's a ways out.
We actually set down what they haven't talked about it. They might be you or at least for them to use it
stuff, so
Yeah
No, I just want to make everybody aware that it's like speak now or forever old your piece
Yes, that's all I have so 14 a journey post second